## **Hammad Afzal**

### **Summary**

A seasoned Full Stack Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience, having a strong ownership mindset, and a passion for learning and adapting to new technologies. Proficient in collaborating effectively with global teams and clients, seeking a new challenge with a versatile tech stack.

in linkedin.com/in/hammad-afzall hammadafzal.cs@gmail.com

\$ +923245963657

💡 Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan.

### Work Experience - 3+ years

**PyflowLabs,** Lahore, Pakistan — Senior Software Engineer May 2023 – Present

- Leading the team for a leading E-commerce and Artwork Fraud Detection Platform and instrumental in developing and maintaining core product microservices on the backend.
- Remarkable performance boost of up to 40% in the Fastify and AWS Lambda by skillfully implementing asynchronous programming techniques.
- · Playing a key role in the architecture and design phases of new modules.
- Successfully working with API Integrations for Magento, SFCC, AWS SDK and AUTHO.
- Managing deployments using Bitbucket pipelines and serverless and deployed versions on AWS.
- · Contributing significantly to production changes and swiftly addressing hotfixes on the frontend with React.
- Actively participating in code review sessions and providing valuable insights for continuous improvement, fostering a culture of collaboration and excellence within the development team.
- Playing the role of an interviewer, mentor, and trainer, providing valuable guidance, nurturing and training junior developers.

### Foomotion, Lahore, Pakistan — Software Engineer

Aug 2021 - May 2023

- Awarded with Certificate of Appreciation in 2023 for adhering to clean code practices and timely deliveries.
- Worked on the development of UI design and functionalities for an Australian Beef Supply chain management system (Web & Mobile App), leveraging a stack consisting of React JS, React Native, Redux, Cypress, Styled Components, and Chart Js.
- Successfully integrated Restful API's with Redux for seamless data management, employing techniques such as Redux Persist and middleware, ensuring efficient state management and enhancing user experience.
- Demonstrated adeptness in architectural design by implementing low coupling and high cohesion principles, resulting in a robust and scalable system architecture.
- Pioneered the development of a web portal from ground up for a leading Australian Beef Supplier Company. Crafted intuitive UI designs and features using React TS, Cypress, Redux Toolkit, and Styled Components,
- Implemented Laratrust for streamlined role management and Nova for an efficient admin panel, enhancing administrative control and user management capabilities for a Real Estate Growth Management Application.
- Successfully integrated Stripe payment gateway, facilitating secure and seamless payment transactions for users, thereby contributing to enhance user experience and revenue generation.
- Contributed to Integration Testing, Debugging, and Refactoring processes, ensuring the reliability, performance, and maintainability of Web Applications, resulting in improved software quality and reduced technical debt.
- Played a pivotal role in shaping the architecture and design of projects.
- Ensured software reliability by authoring unit tests with PHPUnit and testing developed services.

# **Tech Reacher,** Lahore, Pakistan — Associate Software Engineer July 2019 – April 2020

- Designed and developed a highly accurate Inheritance Calculator Web App, meticulously implementing complex formulas to ensure precise and accurate calculations. Demonstrated proficiency in both frontend and backend development.
- Leveraged HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Javascript to create an intuitive and user-friendly interface for the Inheritance Calculator, enhancing accessibility and usability for users across various devices and platforms.
- Took ownership of the UI design for Darzi Web App, ensuring a seamless and visually appealing user experience, while also implementing key functionalities to streamline order management processes.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to understand requirements and translated into actionable features and functionalities within the Darzi application, showcasing strong communication and problem-solving skills.
- Played a key role in the end-to-end development lifecycle of both projects, from initial ideation and design to implementation, testing, and deployment, ensuring the delivery of high-quality solutions that meet and exceed the client expectations.

### **Certifications and Awards**

- AWS Certified.
- Certificate of Appreciation at Foomotion and TechReacher.
- Principal List winner at least two times.
- Volunteering and Fundraising at Roshan-safar.

### Languages

- English (Professional)
- · Urdu (Native)

### **Education**

FAST NUCES, BS (Hons.) Computer Science.

Aug 2017 - July 2021

### **Technical Skills**

Languages/Tools: JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, React JS/TS, React Native (IOS & Android), NodeJS, Fastify, Golang, Redux(Middleware, Thunk and Persist), Redux-Toolkit, Styled Components, Material UI, Charts, Integration Testing, PHP Laravel, Laravel Nova, Laratrust, Restful API's, Cypress, Node-Tap, PHP Unit, Web APIs, RESTful APIs, JWT Auth, Autho, Socket.io, Scrum, Agile Methodologies, Trello, Jira, Clickup, Visual Studio Code, AWS SDK, Docker, Docker Compose, Microservices, OOP, Data Structures. Design Patterns, Swagger, Figma, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Uno CSS.

**Database Servers:** SQL Server, SQLite, PostgreSQL **Version Control:** Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Gitlab

Cloud Services: AWS Lambda, AWS ElastiCache, AWS DynamoDB, AWS SQS, AWS S3, AWS API Gateway

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MacOS